To be continued...
I was fine up until then.
You treated those tryouts like a get-along club.
I couldn't focus because you wanted to goof off.
I would have passed if it wasn't for you.
Uh, what on earth is he talking about?
How did talentless losers like you make it into a Spirion?
Kaneda!
Stop it.
You didn't make the team because you weren't good enough.
Quit trying to blame everyone else for your screw-ups.
Tachibana.
At least I've scored seven goals as a forward in the Tokyo Metropolis League.
Word on the street is that you haven't scored a single goal, even though you've played in every game.
How unfortunate.
It must be hard trying to fit into a strong club, one you don't deserve to be in.
I bet you're regretting it now, aren't you?
Well?
Oh.
I guess so you're, at least, while you're up in this, I think.
It wasn't because of me.
Bye.
I'm feeling bad for you.
Oh!
Bye.
Cachibana.
I guess that's not so bad, Tachibana. Better than Aoi over here.
I heard you've been branded as a failure among forwards, and now they've got you playing defense.
Man, that's pathetic. I always knew you'd turn out to be the most useless. Way to go.
Hey, that's enough.
You don't know what you're talking about.
I'm on the same team as Tachibana and Otomo, and they're amazing players.
I've thought so ever since the tryouts.
Anyone who can't see that doesn't know jack about being a strong soccer player.
That's so nice of you to say about your fellow teammates, Gold Star.
But we were talking about you.
I suppose it's hard being a waste of space on a team you barely play for.
I may not be playing in matches now, but I'm polishing my skills.
He'll be a tough day for you when I return.
As a fullback, sure.
I play over on the right wing.
Which side can I find you on?
The left.
Oh, yeah? That'll be fun.
We'll be able to face off against each other.
If they put you back in, that is.
I've been waiting a long time for a match against Asperion.
They are going to regret choosing you over me.
I'm gonna crush you, Aoi.
Oh, I guess if you're slacking so hard you aren't playing anymore, you've got nothing to worry about.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Kaneda, wait!
Nagino!
Are you okay with this?
Playing on a team with that jerk?
I'm sorry he said all that stuff.
I wish I could get him to apologize.
But...
No need.
He does know how to talk.
Motivation doesn't matter.
If you commit, then you'll win.
He's strong.
And his confidence is through the roof.
I'm guessing after Asperion rejected him,
he busted his butt to prove them wrong.
He's a lot bigger.
It was like touching steel.
Yeah, we've both worked hard.
Been training our asses off all year.
The whole team did.
Under manager Satake's guidance.
I see.
Musashino was made up of players who weren't strong enough for the J League youth teams.
Coach knew our skills were what mattered.
He helped us build our physiques.
Now that we're all playing on the same level,
no one can beat us.
And that includes you guys.
Well, see ya.
Looking forward to our match.
Nagino.
Manager Satake.
How is he?
I noticed he reacted when I mentioned your name.
He said he wished you would call him once in a while.
Okay, I really need to go now.
Come on, Tachibana.
Kaneda's just a douche and probably isn't nearly as good as he likes to think he is.
Let's get out of here.
How about one for the road?
Say no more, Otomo.
Phil, I guess if you aren't playing anymore, you've got nothing to worry about.
Our goal for the next game is to avoid a fifth loss at all costs.
In order to net all three points, we're starting with an aggressive formation.
We've got midfield first.
Sugawara's going back over the right.
That leaves Otomo on the left.
As for who's going to lead us all to victory.
Uh, hi.
I'm Kenta Yoshitsune and I'll be your captain.
Nice to see all you guys.
And thanks.
My injury sort of wrecked my game something hard.
And, uh, they said playing on B team will keep my skills up while I recover, so...
Whoa, seriously?
Yoshitsune's are forward?
Oh, great.
Now that Yoshitsune's on the team, we could have had the perfect lineup.
But then we go and put that train wreck in as our fullback instead?
Huh?
Hey, where's Aoi hiding?
He couldn't focus, so he went out for a little jog.
What?
Who does that?
Wow, really?
Why on earth is he trying to wear himself out two hours before the game starts?
Someone went jogging?
Yeah, an idiot.
Known as our first-year fullback.
Don't get bent about it!
This is Ashito's sting.
Whenever he needs to think about stuff, he just goes out for a long run.
Sounds like it helps him focus, then.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, well, that's fine.
Hang on, Yoshitsune.
Togashi, you remember what to do, right?
What Nozomi talked about?
Mm-mm.
Moving on to defense.
Togashi, just continue to follow Fukuda's instructions.
Got it.
No attacking allowed until I have the defense covered first, right?
I know it's not easy for you.
It goes against your nature, but you're doing a great job.
Don't lose that focus.
The same goes for this game.
You defend first, and you attack second.
Wasn't planning on changing anything.
You too, Aoi.
Defense comes first.
Got that, fullbacks?
So think hard before you make a move.
At least now we've got Yoshitsune.
Which means even if the defenders don't stretch themselves, we can still score.
So are we cool?
Yeah, sure.
But what I heard Coach say was, as long as I provide a good defense, then I can attack whenever I want.
He mentioned an aggressive formation, didn't he?
Mm-mm.
Pretty sure he meant this lineup.
Tachibana?
Jeez.
You and Aoi, huh?
Really think you first years can handle a game like this?
Look at Tachibana.
Sure, he's getting to play, but do you really think he's going to be at his best out there?
He's been feeling down for a while now.
But what worries me most is Aoi.
What is Nozomi thinking?
Why did he decide to play him this game?
Stop what you're doing right this instant!
What? Why are you expending your energy this way?
You don't have very long until the match starts.
You mentioned before that you felt useless out there at fullback.
I'm wondering if you still feel that way?
Because if you don't give them results in this game, who knows how long they'll bench you!
You will never again play as a forward.
Maybe study Kuribayashi's plays.
Have you watched him much?
I'm gonna crush you, Aoi!
Oh, by the way, I got a message from Hana earlier.
She said she's coming to watch the game today.
The thing is, I actually feel happy.
You were right, you know?
I haven't been able to accept the fact that I'm playing fullback.
And now that I'm a starter, it just felt a bit overwhelming.
For the past month, all I did were those boring head turns.
I got yelled at constantly in training sessions.
I thought maybe I was feeling nervous about the new position.
But I can see now.
It was more than that.
Even though I'm a fullback, it's fine.
I'm okay.
I don't understand.
It's not me at all.
I'm okay.
Okay.
So Hana's coming.
That's cool.
She has to see a good game.
So I need to focus.
My mind's clear now.
Let's go!
He's happy?
That's what he was trying to understand before the game?
But more importantly, why did he only realize that when he heard Hana's name?
It's my first match playing as a fullback.
I used to hate the idea of switching positions.
But it feels like my heart's finally changed somehow.
Like something's about to happen.
Something big.
And I'm ready for it.
What the?
That guy's a forward.
Why is he playing defense?
They need to get a new fullback.
I know.
He's making a mess of the entire team.
Ah!
Did he seriously just fall for that lame freaking fate?
Yes!
Nice one, Togashi!
Hey, Aoi.
Can you at least block the crosses?
I'm losing count of how many you've let through at this point.
It's your job to block opponents from your zone.
Even if it means you have to dive in.
Well, if it isn't my favorite reporter.
Is this really compelling material an insignificant local match?
Hey!
What is up with that?
Ashito, Aoi!
I mean, why is he randomly playing on defense?
He sucks!
I came all the way out here today to watch him play forward.
Damn it!
I really hate defending.
The one-on-ones are killing me.
I have to calm down.
Gotta take a breath.
Breathe, damn it!
I'm just overexcited.
I'm not nervous.
Can we talk about that left back?
Dude, I'm guessing they're short on players.
He's got to be filling in for someone.
It's obvious he's a total noob.
I about died when I heard the forward from the U18 Premier League was playing.
But he's completely harmless.
The entire team's so freaking slow.
It's pretty clear to me why they're on a losing streak these days.
Just don't do what you did last time.
I'm sure you thought it was great, but don't.
I mean, last time I saw him play, he was involved with every single goal the team made!
I was so excited to see him in action!
He's horrible in that position!
Looking all over the place like a paranoid rooster, really?
He should be looking upfield and following the center back's instructions, but no!
You don't understand.
A fullback is just like the Lance and Shogi!
Like the Lance and Shogi or something.
Why are they doing this?
For the past month, I did more than just basic training.
I perfected my head-turning moves.
The wing!
Oh, no!
Ashito!
The trains overwhelm you!
Just stay calm.
What are you doing?
Tackle him!
Calm down.
Just calm down.
You can do it!
Defender!
Otomo!
Don't let them drag you out!
Get in front of number 26!
Right!
Seriously?
What?
Where's he going?
If he's over there, I don't have room to attack.
Look, that's their defensive midfielder.
Can't go there.
My only option is to pass it.
What are you doing?
Tackle him!
He's wrong.
I'm not going to tackle a player.
What I need to tackle is...
The space!
That was a really impressive move he made.
He started running even before the pass.
He read the path of it perfectly.
It's like he could already see the game playing out.
Huh?
Hey, did you see that?
That move Ashito just made.
He's doing really well at defense.
I saw it.
Oh!
Hey, aren't you the girl who showed me around last time?
Is he looking at you?
How rude. What was that about?
Who sees a cute girl that's cheering for him and then ignores them?
He's in the middle of a game. He's trying to concentrate.
My bad. I'm being distracting.
I was right. It worked really well.
Keep eyes on the player with the ball first,
then look to the players without the ball next.
I know it's basic soccer technique, but I get it now.
It makes more sense. It's all about dots.
About players being the dots.
Well, more like where they're standing.
Then if you connect the dots with a line,
that line is where the spaces are.
If there aren't any good spaces, then all you have are stagnant dots.
No point in tackling a dot that won't move.
You gotta run to block the space they're gonna try and get to.
That'll be way more effective.
Dang it!
Azito! They're countering!
So when I'm turning my head,
I have to note the spaces the opponent might be planning to use,
not just their positioning.
Over there!
Hey! What?
What the...
Are you blind? That's a foul!
Owie!
Why would you let them draw you out like that?
You just left a stupid amount of space open in your area!
Players are constantly moving and changing strategies,
so the spaces they want to use are always shifting as well.
Was my interception earlier a coincidence?
Just pure luck?
Owie!
Come here.
Tell me.
How did you fail this time?
You had one successful interception.
Why do you think that is?
Well, I, um...
On that particular move,
did you look at the other players?
Of course I did!
That's how I planned.
I knew where the ball was gonna go,
and so I blocked it.
Right.
It was the perfect solution.
Huh?
So was the instruction you gave Otomo just before.
During that play,
you changed Otomo's direction.
You told him to head out to the left.
Because that blocked the route they were planning to use,
and they couldn't link up.
Isn't that right?
Um, yes, sir.
Otomo was gonna head to the middle as planned,
but I saw that Shimizu was already there covering it.
Then what?
Well then...
The opponent had to give up on the wing,
so the only play he could make was to move centrally.
But Tachibana was on his way from behind.
Of course, Shimizu was already in a mega-strong position.
After that, there were hardly any moves left
that the opponent could even make.
So, yeah.
You really do have good vision.
Oh?
Because you see it so well,
I want you to take it one step further, okay?
Two times during the game now,
you saw the space.
It was successful one time, but not the other.
So what did you do differently?
Oh.
I get it.
We're the ones in control!
Hurry it up!
Let's go for the opener!
Damn it!
It seems like no one on our team
is getting any time on the ball!
Otomo!
Go a little more central!
Trust me, Takashima and I have this side covered!
Shimizu!
I'm gonna mark their number 26!
Okay, got it.
What made that first interception successful
was that I used the players around me.
The reason I failed
was because when I spotted the space,
I ran to it myself.
And that created a wide opening in my zone,
which the other guy ran into.
Since I'm in back,
I can see all of the players and spaces.
I can use this to my advantage
and block those spaces
by shouting instructions to my teammates!
Hey, Otomo!
You gotta shuffle further center!
They're about to come for that space!
Someone, please cover!
Anyone!
Ugh!
One minute you play like a noob
and the next you're amazing.
You're a weird first year.
Thanks for that!
It's quite motivating!
Wait, what did he say?
Anyway,
let's go score some goals!
Not a bad return there.
Where do you think you're going, punk?
Nowhere if he's blocked!
Oh, no!
Those two are coming for him!
Yoshitsune!
Pass!
They have you covered!
My gosh.
I guess the B team isn't ready
for advanced moves.
That's too bad.
Yoshitsune plays at a much higher level.
When he has the ball,
the others just need to cover the open spaces.
See how they're all facing the same way?
That's because the opponents
are stuck behind them.
Yoshitsune!
Intercept!
We can't let him hold on to it
for too long!
He didn't fall!
Nice try!
This guy's a piece of work.
He just faked those jerks out on his own
that created all this open space for us.
Back at ya!
He's the kind of player everyone can trust and rely on.
Everything a forward should be.
How's he do it?
No way I could ever be like that.
Yoshitsune!
Huh?
Great game.
I want to be like you.
And I sincerely mean that.
Please teach me how.
Hmm.
Wait, don't tell me.
You're that guy.
Defense.
Aoi, right?
A lot makes sense after seeing you play.
Huh?
Fukuda, he speaks highly of you
to the A-team.
Listen, you don't have to be like me.
You're following the path you're supposed to
all on your own.
Next time on Awashi, Wind of Change.